A few people stayed up. That's good.
Good to see y'all.
Fire away.
>> Mike, talk about Josiah Troder. What uh
would you like about him? Only two year
worth of experience. You see a lot of
these college players staying in for
five and six years sometimes. What What
made him come out of the draft and and
what did you like about him? Yeah, I I
mean I'll say like this we drafted three
21 year olds, so that's it's been a a
rare instance recently with the co
stuff, but uh I think Jeremiah, he's
just been groomed to to play football
his whole life, you know, growing up
with his dad and his brother, you know,
getting drafted a few years ago. And um
he had made a well-informed decision is
what I would say. Like he he thought he
was ready to come out and we spent a lot
of time with him through this process
and um his play on the field dictated
that too, I think. How much are you
influenced by the relationship like with
Mike Caldwell and and stuff like that?
>> Yeah, I mean I think all that stuff
helps, right? Just to try to get to know
the player. Um yeah, Mike had a
relationship with him. Todd has a
relationship with his dad, too. Um you
know, and again, we spent a lot of time
with him, too, and just came away
feeling really comfortable. But I think
all that matters, you know, just again
trying to find out everything we can
about these kids and and uh that played
a part in it. the perception is that you
guys needed to improve um some of your
pass defense inside with with the
linebacker position. I know you got
picked up some free agents obviously,
but like for for Troder seem to be more
of a of a run player right now at least,
right?
>> Yeah. I mean, I I would say that's
that's fair, but I also think that he he
can play in coverage. I think he's
that's a little bit of a misnomer and
you know, I don't know if it's the the
narrative that the media is putting out,
but like he's actually pretty good at
it. Now, that being said, he's an old
school downhill Mike backer that can
play the run, which is hard to find
nowadays. I mean, with the college game,
the way it's went, it's all lateral and
everybody's looking for the speed stuff.
And to us, he has enough speed to play
in our our league. Um, now, if you said,
is he a better run defender than than a
pass defender? I would say, yeah, that's
probably fair, but we think he has the
capability to be a three down
linebacker.
>> Talk about his blitzing ability in in
that matter.
>> Yep. And I would say that's that's a big
part of his game, too. I mean, he he
understands how to rush the passer and
and he can go through running back's
faces if he chooses to or he can make a
miss. So, that's going to be a plus for
Todd on third downs. And I mean, you
guys have seen the way that he uses our
inside backers when Devin was here. And
I mean, I would I would anticipate
Josiah having a lot of production in
that phase
>> with with the fact that I mean, he's
only had like two years of college ball
experience. Would you expect him to kind
of grow in in his coverage, in his
recognition, and his instincts in that
department?
>> Yeah, 100%. I mean, all these guys are
like, like I said, when I started, we
drafted three 21 year olds, and we think
the upside with all of them are is is
huge. So, um, yeah, but I would say that
he also has played the game for a long
time and again has been kind of groomed
from from a young age. So, he's he's
pretty far advanced, I would say, in
that in that area.
>> I don't know if you could also speak to
the the because I I understand he's had
a few knee injuries between college. I
know in 2023 he had a torn I think it
was an ACL and then I think he had like
it was an MCL as well or like I mean did
you guys feel comfortable? I'm guessing
you felt comfortable with the medical.
>> Yeah, I mean I would say anytime we get
asked a question like that the answer is
always going to be yes. We're
comfortable with it. Otherwise, we
wouldn't even mess around with it. I
mean our doctors and athletic trainers,
they do a heck of a job and they spend
tons of time on all these guys. So if we
select somebody, we're we're certainly
comfortable with
>> it. What do you see out of his maybe
leadership potential maybe further down
the road? you know, where's the green
dot? And, you know, you see him talking
to us, especially with the linebacker
room that obviously lost a big-time
leader, you know, maybe down the line.
What do you see out of him in that
sense?
>> Yeah, I mean, it's I'm never going to
compare anybody to Levonte David, first
of all, but uh he uh he has those
qualities though as far as the potential
to be have an impact on our defense and
the in the locker room as a whole. Um
he's just he's he just gets the game,
too. So he's if all the the resources we
talked to or the the sources we talked
to at the school spoke very highly of
him and not only his ability to learn
but also his ability to help others
learn and he would come in every week
and have it like a cheat sheet and tips
for the other players in the room and
helping them out. So he's well on his
way to being a leader now. He's got to
get here and and get in the locker room
and prove it to the to these veterans.
But uh he's got a chance to be pretty
good. I think
>> Mike, in losing Evans, you guys seem to
need a true ex receiver. So, is Hurst
obviously fill that role and what is it
you you really like about Yeah,
>> because your room is
>> plentiful as it is.
>> So, first of all, with Mike, like we're
never ever going to try to replace Mike,
but but you do try to replace size and
speed, which Mike had, and and we think
that Ted has that, too. So Ted's a he's
a small school guy that, you know,
started out Vald Dasa, transferred to
Georgia State. Um, played a couple years
there. Had opportunities to go, you
know, to bigger schools with the NIL
stuff and and stayed loyal to Georgia
State, which it's kind of refreshing a
little bit in this day and age that uh
that guys choose to do that sometimes.
Now, you can look at it the other way
that he's not choosing to go up and play
against the best competition and stuff
like that, but a guy like Ted goes to
the Senior Bowl and does that and then,
you know, proves that he can do that as
well. So, he's just kind of checked the
boxes every step of the way. Um, and at
the same time, he's still has a lot to
improve on, you know, the route running,
the I mean, he's he's got he's just kind
of a raw player, but he's a he's a big
fast athletic guy that's willing to
learn and and we're excited about him.
>> The I mean, for him, is it is it the
contested catches? is that I mean I know
again there's no replacing Mike but you
know he's also that guy that if you need
to score quickly and you can get him you
know single coverage downfield you know
you're taking that shot. Um I know that
he has produced a lot of of catches of
20 plus yards. I mean is that kind of I
guess what you could envision for him?
>> Yeah, I think so. I mean again like
we're talking about bringing a guy into
a crowded room to use your your quote
earlier. I mean, we're not expecting him
to come in and just, you know, take over
and and have to to be a big part of our
offense. Now, that being said, there's
nothing that says he can't. If he comes
in and proves himself, he, you know,
whatever role he has, it's going to be
on what he's ready for and how he works
and proves himself. But, but yes, he is
a big guy that's 6'4, 210 and and runs
in the 44. So, that's intriguing to us,
you know. Um, and again, the downfield
stuff, he's got really good ball skills,
too. So, not only can he get over the
top and beat guys deep, but if it is
contested, he has the ability to make
those catches. So, um he's got a lot lot
of traits that we look for at at the X
position, which is what Mike played, and
um and we'll just see how it all all
plays out.
>> So, a factor like is is a big slot. I
know that that Zach likes to use that.
That's how we use Drake London and
Atlanta quite a bit with slant catches,
getting yards after catch with that
speed.
>> Yeah. I mean, again, like I have
complete faith in in our coaches, uh,
that they're going to put him in great
positions and and I wouldn't rule that
out. I mean, I just think that, you
know, there's there's three, sometimes
four, sometimes five white outs on the
field and they're going to put them in
spots where they're going to be able to
succeed and and he has a skill set to do
that. You know, it's just when you see
the size and the speed, everybody thinks
outside, but we've been pretty
successful putting bigger guys inside as
well, you know, and Chris can do that,
Mecca can do that. like we got some guys
that can do it, but if to to get
matchups, that's what this game's all
about is matchups and and he has the
ability to do a lot of different things.
>> Do you guys let Jason trade this year?
Um how how important was for you guys to
get one of those extra day day three
picks in
>> We were actually joking about that. It
was time for us to trade back and get an
extra pick with Jason. Uh that's that's
always interesting, especially in a
draft like this where I think it
probably wasn't like topheavy, but I
think there's a lot of depth and a lot
of quality players in those, you know,
mid rounds to even the fifth round,
which, you know, we picked up that pick.
So, it's always good to get more picks.
I mean, we feel like we can we can hit
on those later rounds. Our scouting
department does a heck of a job of, you
know, of identifying those guys that so
that we look at them, too. And and uh
we've had a pretty good hit rate around
here recent. you guys sweating it out as
as as 84 came back up and
>> uh I mean you're always going to sweat
it out. Like that's just kind of part of
the draft because you're dealing with 31
other teams that are, you know, doing
the same thing you are. So um but at the
same time, we trade back. We know that
there's a chance we're going to lose
him, but so we're always prepared to
have other guys lined up if that's the
case. But but yes, when uh when our pick
came up and he was still there, it was
pretty pretty exciting in the room.
>> What did you see first in the in the
senior bowl? you mentioned, you know,
stepping up and playing up against, you
know, tougher competition. What What did
you see from him there?
>> Just his ability to compete and and and
hold up versus those guys. Um it wasn't
too big for him, which is always kind of
what you look for from smaller school
players if they can go there and compete
and it was like I mean I always use Alli
Maretta in a perfect example like Alli
went there coming from Hobart College
and struggled the first day but by the
end of the week he was he was kicking
everybody's ass. So that was always it's
it's those small school guys that's what
they have to do. that first of all, they
have to dominate their their level of
competition. If they're not doing that,
then it's hard to project them in our
league. But if they are, and then they
can go to the Senior Bowl and or the any
of these all-star games really and hold
their own, then it gives you, you know,
encouragement that they'll be able to do
it in our level.
>> Mike, last night we saw a pretty excited
uh Bucks war room and selecting Ruben
Bane Jr., uh what are your thoughts uh
overall about being able to land him in
the process in which you you got him?
>> Yeah, that's that's probably one of the
more excited draft rooms I've been
around of. I mean, it just when you get
a player of his quality, um, where we
were picking, I think that's what where
the excitement comes from. Um, because a
lot of us didn't expect him to be there.
We just assumed he was going to be long
gone. But again, that's why we prepare
for every scenario. And we did a lot of
work on Ruben just like we do every
other prospect. And, um, it it's just
fun to to see him there. Uh, because we
think we're getting one of the better
pass rushers in this draft. and he
brings a lot of attitude and and effort
and just some nastiness that we've kind
of been lacking a little bit I think on
defense and I would say that Jeremiah
has that stuff too just what I was
talking about the run stuffer downhill
type player so uh it's exciting to add
those two young guys to our defense
>> speak of that you look at edge rusher
and linebacker and those were two of the
biggest needs coming into this this
offseason with Bane in the first round
with Troder in the second round how does
it feel how for you guys are you
comfortable knowing that hey we might
have just locked up two starters
for the first and and fix this position
that was one of the ones that we kind of
set into this offse to fix.
>> Yeah, I I mean I think that that's what
you always go into a draft hoping that
the needs match up with the best player
and I think that's kind of what happened
in this draft. I mean I don't think that
Jason we never force things and again I
don't think we did this year either. I
just think that just happened to be, you
know, the best player was there and it's
two positions that, you know, I would
agree we probably needed to to upgrade a
little bit. And um yeah, it's pretty
exciting to think that, you know, and
we'll see. I mean, it's too early to
call them starters, but you're drafting
in the first and second round, you're
expecting to come in and compete for
that role. So, we'll see how it all
plays out, but yeah, it's pretty
exciting.
>> What was what was it that sold you on on
Bane?
>> I mean, because this is this is a class
where there's a lot of of edge rushers
and we've seen so many
>> so many come off the board. He's
different because just because of the
body type, you know, he's a shorter,
thicker guy, but his his power is
unmatched in my opinion. Like he he has
the ability to go through blockers
faces, which is a it's a good place to
start as a pass rusher in our league. I
mean, everybody talks about all the
speed guys that can can run the hoops,
but it's hard to get around Tristan
Warfs. I mean, he's just as athletic as
a lot of these guys, and it's tough and
it's tough to get around him. So, you
got to be able to incorporate some kind
of power into your game, and he has that
already. So now it's just a matter of
him continuing to hone his skills and um
and be able to to use change ups, which
he's already done a lot of. I mean, he
had a really good defensive line coach
there at Miami, and he's probably pretty
far ahead of the game compared to a lot
of guys.
>> Mike, there were a couple other uh
linebackers there for the taking in the
second round, but what was the the
factor in selecting Josiah over some of
the other guys?
>> I mean, in the end, it's about the
player and the person, right? and we
just thought he was one of those guys
that matched up with both of them. Like
he has, you know, he has a lot of
ability to play in this league. And
again, I just talked about the toughness
and the and the attitude that a guy like
him brings to our defense. Um, and then
the person and the leader that we think
that he could potentially be and the
teammate. I mean, he he just fits kind
of the the I am that man that we use a
lot around here.
>> Mike, with with Troder, I think he had
27 reps on the bench at Combine. It's
the most by a linebacker in like four
years at Combine. I just want to ask you
about his physicality and what that
brings to the position for you guys.
>> Yeah, I mean again I think that's you
you don't see that a lot in co the
college game now like I said before. I
mean it's just the ability to go on and
take on these big offensive linemen and
use that ability to press and get off
blocks. I mean he he's pretty rare in
that in that sense from from a college
guy coming out like um so he's just to
me like he's so much further ahead of
the game being able to adapt to a pro
style game as opposed to what you know a
lot of these guys coming out of college.
It's it's probably a bigger learning
curve than what he's going to have.
>> How do you kind of weigh what his
strengths are versus because as he
mentioned like there are other guys on
the that were still available like CJ
Allen he was still on the board I think
at the time. Um I know that Jacob
Rodriguez was already had already been
picked but like how do you weigh like
what his strengths are? You know he's a
thumper and and very physical uh versus
like okay maybe getting more of um like
ancilloney type you know where he's more
of a of a coverage type of a player.
like how did you kind of I guess come to
the decision of of which style you
wanted, you know, cuz two in free
agency, you know, you signed different
guys,
>> right?
>> I mean, there's so many things that go
into selecting a player and I would say
that we had all those guys pretty
closely clumped together. I mean,
they're all really good football
players. So, um, when choosing one over
the other, it just comes down to the
conversations that we have as a scouting
department and then the conversations we
have with the coaches and the
comfortability everybody has and and
we're so prepared going into the draft
that we kind of know the way we're going
to take him and and then we just kind of
stick to that. But I mean, Josiah, just
all the stuff I've already talked about
with the the phys physicality, the the
the ability to play downhill, the
ability to coverage, the ability to
blitz, like all those things are just
intriguing. And um it was pretty
unanimous with the coaches in in the
personnel department.
>> He's 21, but he only has two years of
college experience and and typically you
don't see that a lot. Any is he just
precocious? Any any kind of trepidation
there about a guy that's only played two
years college football?
No, I mean I I think Rick, we used to
see that a lot more. You know, I think
the co stuff has changed that. So, we've
kind of gotten away from it and you you
have a lot of these guys who are, you
know, 23, 24, 25 and have bu played for
five or six years and um you know, but
five, six, seven. Yeah. I mean, like,
but that's that's kind of the way the
the college game used to be because we
had so many underassman coming out and
not all of them are three-ear starters.
So,
>> you saw it a lot more and and again,
it's it's it's on a case-byase basis and
and I think that Josiah has proven that,
you know, he can play at a high level
and and uh just from a mental
standpoint, again, he's so he's so far
ahead of the curve, I believe,
>> as far as the way the board plays out,
shakes out tomorrow for you guys and
some of your perceived needs, are you
guys feel comfortable going in tomorrow
with some with some of the the spots
that you feel like you need to add to?
>> Yeah, for sure. And I kind of hit on
earlier. I think this is a pretty deep
draft and there's a lot of depth that
you know at a lot of different positions
that and again like we're never going to
force things and that's the beauty of
tomorrow and and picking up another
fifth round pick and maybe we can talk
Jason into trading again and get a few
more. But um but yeah, that's that's
always exciting and and again that's
kind of when your your scouting
department kind of kicks in in those
later rounds and and and uh it's always
fun and even going into undrafted free
agency like all that stuff is a blast
for for scouts. with you guys like being
really intentional about the type of
like personalities you're bringing in,
especially like on defense this off
seasonason, wanting those kickers. Um,
how did that kind of I guess
>> well, I didn't know if I was allowed to
say it on here, but like how does that
how did that kind of, you know, change
like your your draft board? I mean, do
you put like maybe this year personality
traits uh a little bit higher than maybe
you would, you know, ability? Like how I
guess I'm curious how that that kind of
impacted you guys this year. Yeah, I I
think that it's like we we do the same
thing every year. And now I shouldn't
say that. We we're always evolving,
right? Like I mean, we we try to stick
to our core principles and bring in the
right kind of guys, but at the same
time, they they're not all going to be
choir boys and and you know,
>> watch those last year, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah, they are. But they all are
competitive. So, and if you look at some
of the greatest defensive guys in in
Bucks history, they were not choir boys.
And
>> so, it's it's fine. I mean, and I think
we have a really strong um coaching
staff, a really strong locker room, you
know, that can handle some some big
personalities now. And um but we're
always going to stick to our core values
and, you know, try to bring in the right
kind of guys.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Appreciate it.